<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Life on Artur Kondas</title><link>https://akondas.com/tags/life/</link><description>Recent content in Life on Artur Kondas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akondas.com/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Heads Low, Hopes High</title><link>https://akondas.com/blog/heads-low-hopes-high/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akondas.com/blog/heads-low-hopes-high/</guid><description>Hunting for Sunrise In 2013, when I was merely a 19 year old lad, I had a band. The band was called Sunrise Hunters and it has released literally one EP before we disbanded:</description><content>&lt;h2 id="hunting-for-sunrise">Hunting for Sunrise&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In 2013, when I was merely a 19 year old lad, I had a band. The band was called Sunrise Hunters and it has released literally one EP before we disbanded:&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_20T4qx6jxY?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We had really big hopes and ambitions for our small venture; heck, we&amp;rsquo;ve even got to do two small tours, created some buzz and then it all went down the drain - but at least the songs stayed with us!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Bear in mind, touring in Poland is having two weekends of gigs and calling it a tour.
Yeah.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>But, throughout my life, the mantra stuck. Up until a few years ago, when I&amp;rsquo;ve got so ambitious, that switching jobs every year and getting raises basically every half a year was a MUST.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The question is - is that the right approach?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hopes-high">Hopes High&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I do believe in setting goals so astronomically high, that other people will look at you and say &lt;code>you can't do it, it's impossible!&lt;/code>.
My thinking process is that if you set the bar so high you can&amp;rsquo;t really reach it, eventually you&amp;rsquo;ll find a way to do so.
For me, setting achievable goals doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t push you outside of the comfort zone - and getting comfortable means getting stale.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goals I&amp;rsquo;ve set for my 40th birthday (which is in 10 years, so that&amp;rsquo;s a LOOONG time) are, well, in the grand scheme of things, outside of the Solar System.
The thing I&amp;rsquo;ve learned throughout my life is that approach works for me way better than small goals and getting them signed off every now and then.
It&amp;rsquo;s basically an approach of giving a fuck about things you want to give a fuck about and then not giving a single one about the stuff you don&amp;rsquo;t want to care about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This approach has one, extremely bad, problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="heads-low">Heads Low&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you get too cocky, then you&amp;rsquo;ll get burned. And the issue is, that getting burned slow you down.
In the current modern world, where we&amp;rsquo;re pushed to be hustlers, have side gigs, work, work, work, it&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible to slow down.
And the real power of this approach comes from understanding when to push the brakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, I did a small thing for my company, &lt;a href="https://www.form3.tech/">Form3&lt;/a>, where &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/form3-financial-cloud/?miniCompanyUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afs_miniCompany%3A15156804&amp;lipi=urn%3Ali%3Apage%3Acompanies_company_posts_index%3B502de21e-6523-4144-9173-ddd155dbf3d5">you get to know me a little bit better in 60 seconds or less&lt;/a>.
The exercise was a bit of an interesting journey for me, when preparing the answers to the questions, I had a chance to recap all the things I&amp;rsquo;ve done in the last 10 years or so.
Then it hit me - I haven&amp;rsquo;t stopped a bit for a while now!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="pumping-the-brakes">Pumping The Brakes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Although this post will be extremely counter-intuitive, with me doing conferences this year and events and whatnot, I feel like you, the fellow reader, would also benefit from doing such thing - which is stopping a bit, replanning and then going for the kill.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had a few really good chats with some friends of mine, whose opinion I care about, and the general consensus was exactly the same - just chill for a bit.
And this is what I&amp;rsquo;m going to do - chill for a bit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whatever happens, happens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everything, eventually, works itself out.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="stepping-on-the-gas">Stepping On The Gas&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean we have to hit a hard stop. Again, it&amp;rsquo;s all about choosing what do you want to give a fuck about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, please, give a fuck.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keep your head low, keep your hopes high, and let&amp;rsquo;s go!&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>