<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hobby on Artur Kondas</title><link>https://akondas.com/tags/hobby/</link><description>Recent content in hobby on Artur Kondas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akondas.com/tags/hobby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Love The Job You Hate</title><link>https://akondas.com/blog/love-the-job-you-hate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akondas.com/blog/love-the-job-you-hate/</guid><description>New year, new me ey? I want to give you another angle on ditch your job and follow your dreams idea.</description><content>&lt;p>New year, new me ey?
I want to give you another angle on &lt;em>ditch your job and follow your dreams&lt;/em> idea.
And this is coming from a guy who used to do my passion for a living and have reworked my idea about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you need a soundtrack for this post, I really recommend &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2dSBarxs3F8">Honne&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="keep-your-expectations-in-check">Keep Your Expectations In Check&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll go right out of the gate and drop the truthbombs now - if your side-hussle is not a full time gig and/or you&amp;rsquo;re not 100% honest with yourself - the mean rate of return from your hobby might not be the greatest.
You can get a lot from your after-work gig, but it requires time. The more you put in, the more you get out - it&amp;rsquo;s basically like investing in stock market, you can&amp;rsquo;t get a million from $1 investment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, you can, but it requires a lot of time and even more luck.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="not-every-hobby-has-to-be-a-hussle">Not Every Hobby Has To Be A Hussle&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>And this is where we get into the actual topic of this post - &lt;strong>not every hobby has to be a hussle&lt;/strong>.
We&amp;rsquo;re living in a world, in which, everywhere you go, you see an influencer, telling you how well they&amp;rsquo;re doing living off their passion.
Everything is covered in hyperachiever-sauce with a hint of desperation.
You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t feel pushed to make your knitting hobby into a full-time Etsy shop, or your after-work small code sessions into a career.
The reason is simple - when you do cross the line and turn your hobby into work, the things change - suddenly, you have to manage an inventory or deal with customers or have a Sprint retrospective every week - and then you end up hating the job you&amp;rsquo;ve thought you&amp;rsquo;ll love.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="love-the-job-you-hate">Love The Job You Hate&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Most of us used to be in a place, where you&amp;rsquo;ve stared a new interest in something and then thought about making it a full time thing.
The problem with this is that when the adrenaline and the dopamine kicks in, you get a massive tunnel vision - only the way you think about the goal is right and there&amp;rsquo;s no other way of getting to the finish line.
When all of that starts to pick up the slack, there&amp;rsquo;s an overwhelming feeling of dread and annoyance with your current job.
You&amp;rsquo;re starting to feel like it&amp;rsquo;s restricting you and not allowing you to really fly and do what you love.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although the title of this paragraph might be a tad misleading/triggering for some, what I want to convey is that you need to &lt;strong>give yourself some time&lt;/strong>.
If you&amp;rsquo;re in a dead-end/really bad job, most of the time, it&amp;rsquo;s actually better to quit right out of the gate (and welcome to this post&amp;rsquo;s multiverse!) and either grab another part-time gig or YOLO it and just go with the newfound passion.
But if you&amp;rsquo;re in a somewhat stable, warm and cosy gig, embrace it for a while.
Take it from me, before, I&amp;rsquo;ve used to live from my passion, used to work 18hrs a day, balancing finishing uni, teaching full time and working full time.
Now, I&amp;rsquo;ve found the path for me and I know how to get where I want to get.
But it took me, literally, years to get to this point.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="its-ok-to-pivot">It&amp;rsquo;s OK To Pivot&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Okay, let&amp;rsquo;s say, right now, you&amp;rsquo;re knee deep in your journey, you know the angles, but then, the inevitable comes and you&amp;rsquo;re starting to feel like that&amp;rsquo;s not the thing.
Maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve spent a month or a year on this hobby, but the next thing feels like it might actually be the one.
What you should do then?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, do the same thing as the one when you&amp;rsquo;ve started the previous thing - explore.
Once you&amp;rsquo;ll get a little deeper into the rabbit hole, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to pivot and change direction - always remember, that the things you&amp;rsquo;ve learned so far, allows for a better foundation of the next thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="follow-your-gut">Follow Your Gut&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>All of that above can be dismissed with just a right feeling and the perfect combination of perseverance and luck.
If you feel like you&amp;rsquo;re ready to follow your passion, that it&amp;rsquo;s the greatest thing in the world, it feels right AND you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to survive before you&amp;rsquo;ll get to the top - &lt;strong>do it!&lt;/strong>
The older I get, the more I go with not even &lt;em>doing things safe&lt;/em> but &lt;em>doing things smart&lt;/em> - I want the things that I do to bring some value, I want to be proud of them and I really don&amp;rsquo;t want to restrict my growth in other avenues of my life.
I did both ways (doing the bare minimum and YOLO) and I&amp;rsquo;ve found doing things smart to have the golden ratio between these ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now it&amp;rsquo;s your turn to figure it out!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Liked that post? Consider &lt;a href="https://akondas.com/subscribe/">subscribing&lt;/a> to get notifications when new things arrive here!&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>