<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>jobs on Artur Kondas</title><link>https://akondas.com/tags/jobs/</link><description>Recent content in jobs on Artur Kondas</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akondas.com/tags/jobs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Heads Low, Hopes High</title><link>https://akondas.com/blog/heads-low-hopes-high/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akondas.com/blog/heads-low-hopes-high/</guid><description>Hunting for Sunrise In 2013, when I was merely a 19 year old lad, I had a band. The band was called Sunrise Hunters and it has released literally one EP before we disbanded:</description><content>&lt;h2 id="hunting-for-sunrise">Hunting for Sunrise&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In 2013, when I was merely a 19 year old lad, I had a band. The band was called Sunrise Hunters and it has released literally one EP before we disbanded:&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_20T4qx6jxY" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We had really big hopes and ambitions for our small venture; heck, we&amp;rsquo;ve even got to do two small tours, created some buzz and then it all went down the drain - but at least the songs stayed with us!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Bear in mind, touring in Poland is having two weekends of gigs and calling it a tour.
Yeah.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>But, throughout my life, the mantra stuck. Up until a few years ago, when I&amp;rsquo;ve got so ambitious, that switching jobs every year and getting raises basically every half a year was a MUST.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The question is - is that the right approach?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hopes-high">Hopes High&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I do believe in setting goals so astronomically high, that other people will look at you and say &lt;code>you can't do it, it's impossible!&lt;/code>.
My thinking process is that if you set the bar so high you can&amp;rsquo;t really reach it, eventually you&amp;rsquo;ll find a way to do so.
For me, setting achievable goals doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t push you outside of the comfort zone - and getting comfortable means getting stale.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goals I&amp;rsquo;ve set for my 40th birthday (which is in 10 years, so that&amp;rsquo;s a LOOONG time) are, well, in the grand scheme of things, outside of the Solar System.
The thing I&amp;rsquo;ve learned throughout my life is that approach works for me way better than small goals and getting them signed off every now and then.
It&amp;rsquo;s basically an approach of giving a fuck about things you want to give a fuck about and then not giving a single one about the stuff you don&amp;rsquo;t want to care about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This approach has one, extremely bad, problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="heads-low">Heads Low&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you get too cocky, then you&amp;rsquo;ll get burned. And the issue is, that getting burned slow you down.
In the current modern world, where we&amp;rsquo;re pushed to be hustlers, have side gigs, work, work, work, it&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible to slow down.
And the real power of this approach comes from understanding when to push the brakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, I did a small thing for my company, &lt;a href="https://www.form3.tech/">Form3&lt;/a>, where &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/form3-financial-cloud/?miniCompanyUrn=urn%3Ali%3Afs_miniCompany%3A15156804&amp;amp;lipi=urn%3Ali%3Apage%3Acompanies_company_posts_index%3B502de21e-6523-4144-9173-ddd155dbf3d5">you get to know me a little bit better in 60 seconds or less&lt;/a>.
The exercise was a bit of an interesting journey for me, when preparing the answers to the questions, I had a chance to recap all the things I&amp;rsquo;ve done in the last 10 years or so.
Then it hit me - I haven&amp;rsquo;t stopped a bit for a while now!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="pumping-the-brakes">Pumping The Brakes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Although this post will be extremely counter-intuitive, with me doing conferences this year and events and whatnot, I feel like you, the fellow reader, would also benefit from doing such thing - which is stopping a bit, replanning and then going for the kill.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had a few really good chats with some friends of mine, whose opinion I care about, and the general consensus was exactly the same - just chill for a bit.
And this is what I&amp;rsquo;m going to do - chill for a bit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whatever happens, happens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everything, eventually, works itself out.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="stepping-on-the-gas">Stepping On The Gas&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean we have to hit a hard stop. Again, it&amp;rsquo;s all about choosing what do you want to give a fuck about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, please, give a fuck.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keep your head low, keep your hopes high, and let&amp;rsquo;s go!&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>On The Importance Of A Good Feedback</title><link>https://akondas.com/blog/on-the-importance-of-a-good-feedback/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akondas.com/blog/on-the-importance-of-a-good-feedback/</guid><description>This post is trying out a completely new approach to writing which I&amp;rsquo;ll be trialing for a while now, with a goal to analyse it afterwards.</description><content>&lt;p>This post is trying out a completely new approach to writing which I&amp;rsquo;ll be trialing for a while now,
with a goal to analyse it afterwards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enjoy!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="the-mirror">The Mirror&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Feedback is like a mirror that shows us how others see us.
Do we look fabulous, or do we have spinach in our teeth?
It&amp;rsquo;s not always easy to hear what others think of us, but feedback is an essential tool in personal and professional growth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes, even if it&amp;rsquo;s harsh, a feedback that points you to the right direction, might mark a pivotal point in your life.
After all, we don&amp;rsquo;t know all and we want to grow.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-karaoke-machine">The Karaoke Machine&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Have you ever wondered how you come across to others?
Maybe you think you&amp;rsquo;re the life of the party, but others see you as the person who hogs the karaoke machine.
Receiving feedback can give us an objective view of our behavior and help us make adjustments to improve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not always easy to take feedback, though.
It can be as painful as realizing you&amp;rsquo;ve been walking around with your fly open all day.
But if we approach feedback with an open mind and a willingness to learn, we can benefit from the constructive criticism.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="feedback-with-no-value">Feedback With No Value&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>However, not all feedback is created equal.
Non-constructive feedback that focuses on personal attacks, or, even worst, providing no feedback at all or a dismissive one-liner, rather than specific behaviors, doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide any value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s like when someone tells you that your presentation was terrible, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t give you any specific reasons why.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It leaves you feeling frustrated and confused, like when you accidentally put salt instead of sugar in your morning coffee.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To be effective, feedback needs to be specific, actionable, and focused on behaviors that can be changed.
So, the next time you&amp;rsquo;re giving or receiving feedback, make sure it&amp;rsquo;s constructive and provides clear direction for improvement.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="giving-feedback">Giving Feedback&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Have you ever given feedback to someone and felt like you&amp;rsquo;re walking on eggshells?
Providing feedback can be just as challenging as receiving it.
It&amp;rsquo;s hard to strike the right balance between being honest and not hurting someone&amp;rsquo;s feelings.
But when done effectively, giving feedback can be a game-changer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By giving feedback, we give others the opportunity to improve their performance, which can benefit both individuals and organizations.
When we give feedback, we need to make sure we&amp;rsquo;re specific and focus on behaviors that can be changed.
We also need to make sure we&amp;rsquo;re coming from a place of kindness and a desire to help, rather than a desire to criticize.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After all, no one likes being told they&amp;rsquo;re the office clown.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="is-it-really-this-important">Is It Really THIS Important?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In conclusion, feedback is an essential tool for growth and development.
So, don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to ask for feedback and listen to what others have to say.
By embracing feedback as a tool for growth and improvement, we can all become better versions of ourselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And when it comes to giving feedback, remember to be constructive, specific, and kind.
By doing so, we can create a culture of growth and improvement in our personal and professional lives, and avoid the awkward moments of realizing we&amp;rsquo;ve had spinach in our teeth all day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because, sometimes we get the spinach in our teeth. And that&amp;rsquo;s ok!&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Love The Job You Hate</title><link>https://akondas.com/blog/love-the-job-you-hate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akondas.com/blog/love-the-job-you-hate/</guid><description>New year, new me ey? I want to give you another angle on ditch your job and follow your dreams idea.</description><content>&lt;p>New year, new me ey?
I want to give you another angle on &lt;em>ditch your job and follow your dreams&lt;/em> idea.
And this is coming from a guy who used to do my passion for a living and have reworked my idea about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you need a soundtrack for this post, I really recommend &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2dSBarxs3F8">Honne&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="keep-your-expectations-in-check">Keep Your Expectations In Check&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll go right out of the gate and drop the truthbombs now - if your side-hussle is not a full time gig and/or you&amp;rsquo;re not 100% honest with yourself - the mean rate of return from your hobby might not be the greatest.
You can get a lot from your after-work gig, but it requires time. The more you put in, the more you get out - it&amp;rsquo;s basically like investing in stock market, you can&amp;rsquo;t get a million from $1 investment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, you can, but it requires a lot of time and even more luck.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="not-every-hobby-has-to-be-a-hussle">Not Every Hobby Has To Be A Hussle&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>And this is where we get into the actual topic of this post - &lt;strong>not every hobby has to be a hussle&lt;/strong>.
We&amp;rsquo;re living in a world, in which, everywhere you go, you see an influencer, telling you how well they&amp;rsquo;re doing living off their passion.
Everything is covered in hyperachiever-sauce with a hint of desperation.
You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t feel pushed to make your knitting hobby into a full-time Etsy shop, or your after-work small code sessions into a career.
The reason is simple - when you do cross the line and turn your hobby into work, the things change - suddenly, you have to manage an inventory or deal with customers or have a Sprint retrospective every week - and then you end up hating the job you&amp;rsquo;ve thought you&amp;rsquo;ll love.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="love-the-job-you-hate">Love The Job You Hate&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Most of us used to be in a place, where you&amp;rsquo;ve stared a new interest in something and then thought about making it a full time thing.
The problem with this is that when the adrenaline and the dopamine kicks in, you get a massive tunnel vision - only the way you think about the goal is right and there&amp;rsquo;s no other way of getting to the finish line.
When all of that starts to pick up the slack, there&amp;rsquo;s an overwhelming feeling of dread and annoyance with your current job.
You&amp;rsquo;re starting to feel like it&amp;rsquo;s restricting you and not allowing you to really fly and do what you love.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although the title of this paragraph might be a tad misleading/triggering for some, what I want to convey is that you need to &lt;strong>give yourself some time&lt;/strong>.
If you&amp;rsquo;re in a dead-end/really bad job, most of the time, it&amp;rsquo;s actually better to quit right out of the gate (and welcome to this post&amp;rsquo;s multiverse!) and either grab another part-time gig or YOLO it and just go with the newfound passion.
But if you&amp;rsquo;re in a somewhat stable, warm and cosy gig, embrace it for a while.
Take it from me, before, I&amp;rsquo;ve used to live from my passion, used to work 18hrs a day, balancing finishing uni, teaching full time and working full time.
Now, I&amp;rsquo;ve found the path for me and I know how to get where I want to get.
But it took me, literally, years to get to this point.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="its-ok-to-pivot">It&amp;rsquo;s OK To Pivot&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Okay, let&amp;rsquo;s say, right now, you&amp;rsquo;re knee deep in your journey, you know the angles, but then, the inevitable comes and you&amp;rsquo;re starting to feel like that&amp;rsquo;s not the thing.
Maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve spent a month or a year on this hobby, but the next thing feels like it might actually be the one.
What you should do then?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, do the same thing as the one when you&amp;rsquo;ve started the previous thing - explore.
Once you&amp;rsquo;ll get a little deeper into the rabbit hole, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to pivot and change direction - always remember, that the things you&amp;rsquo;ve learned so far, allows for a better foundation of the next thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="follow-your-gut">Follow Your Gut&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>All of that above can be dismissed with just a right feeling and the perfect combination of perseverance and luck.
If you feel like you&amp;rsquo;re ready to follow your passion, that it&amp;rsquo;s the greatest thing in the world, it feels right AND you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to survive before you&amp;rsquo;ll get to the top - &lt;strong>do it!&lt;/strong>
The older I get, the more I go with not even &lt;em>doing things safe&lt;/em> but &lt;em>doing things smart&lt;/em> - I want the things that I do to bring some value, I want to be proud of them and I really don&amp;rsquo;t want to restrict my growth in other avenues of my life.
I did both ways (doing the bare minimum and YOLO) and I&amp;rsquo;ve found doing things smart to have the golden ratio between these ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now it&amp;rsquo;s your turn to figure it out!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Liked that post? Consider &lt;a href="https://akondas.com/subscribe/">subscribing&lt;/a> to get notifications when new things arrive here!&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Don't Be A Dick</title><link>https://akondas.com/blog/dont-be-a-dick/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://akondas.com/blog/dont-be-a-dick/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re a techie, you know that this year has been absolutely red hot when it comes to jobs. But job hunting comes with an absolute crapton of entitlement* - from all sides.&lt;/p></description><content>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re a techie, you know that this year has been absolutely red hot when it comes to jobs. But job hunting comes with an absolute crapton of entitlement* - from all sides.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if entitlement is the right word here but read on to figure out what I want to say!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a really weird and not-so-colourfull world we live in at the moment - the best thing one can do, is &lt;strong>not being a dick&lt;/strong>. What I want to explore is - how not to be a dick when you&amp;rsquo;re either switching jobs or trying to convince somebody to switch jobs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will look from four angles - as an employee who wants to change/is changing jobs, as an employee who wants to retain people, as a recruiter who wants to, well, recruit people and as a human being who&amp;rsquo;s in the middle of it all.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Really, really big disclaimer here:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is all based on my own (and not only) experiences switching jobs here and there, so the view is a little biased. If you feel like you want to add something in the discussion, &lt;a href="mailto:hello@akondas.com">tell me about it!&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="as-an-employee">As an Employee&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>So, that&amp;rsquo;s the seemingly easy bit - &lt;em>I just hand in my notice and fuck-it-all&lt;/em> or, even worst, &lt;em>I&amp;rsquo;ll burn everything down&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The thing is, you can do it with a lot of dignity and with a proper communication. Of course, this assumes that you already had a good rapport with your manager, which - in my opinion - is quintessential in having a nice, lasting tenure in your current company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What you might do:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="start-a-conversation-with-your-manager-about-you-looking-around">Start a conversation with your manager about you looking around.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Worst case scenario (which is highly unlikely to happen) - your manager will be &amp;ldquo;mad&amp;rdquo; (?) at you that you&amp;rsquo;re trying to leave.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Best case scenario - maybe you really don&amp;rsquo;t want to leave but you&amp;rsquo;re feeling like you&amp;rsquo;ve hit the ceiling in your current role or you just need a change of scenery.
There&amp;rsquo;s always a new project, a new team or a new training you can do to ensure that you&amp;rsquo;re still growing in what you do.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="be-open-about-what-youre-after">Be open about what you&amp;rsquo;re after.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This basically goes together with the previous point - if you need something new, be open about it.
Don&amp;rsquo;t be the person that is miserable but won&amp;rsquo;t tell anybody about it (I know it&amp;rsquo;s hard, but it&amp;rsquo;s the right way to grow as a human, really).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="dont-burn-your-bridges">Don&amp;rsquo;t burn your bridges.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this way too many times. There&amp;rsquo;s no virtue in leaving your current place and tearing the house down.
Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how bad your current place is, remember that your manager, their manager and the CEO are still humans. Just be mindful about that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other thing is - you never know where your life will lead you. If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this post, there&amp;rsquo;s a very high chance that (sadly!) you&amp;rsquo;re not a heir to a fortune and you&amp;rsquo;re still figuring things out as they go.
You might find yourself needing help from someone from your old work, or maybe you know that somebody has the skillset that you might need.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And last, but not least, be the bigger person here - if you&amp;rsquo;re finishing your time with the worst company in the whole goddamn world (but they haven&amp;rsquo;t done anything unlawful or really, really, REALLY bad), just say &lt;em>thanks for the time I&amp;rsquo;ve spent with you&lt;/em>, pack your things and go. Whatever happened, happened and you&amp;rsquo;re off to the next big adventure - focus on that!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="as-an-employer">As an Employer&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Okay, this one might be fun - I&amp;rsquo;ve never employed anyone, so this will be mostly &amp;ldquo;how I&amp;rsquo;d like to be treated by the companies I&amp;rsquo;m working for&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Yet another disclaimer here&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please, do not associate these things here to any of my previous, current or future employers. This is based on multitude of years of observations from various viewpoints.
I felt like I need to put it there again.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="listen-to-your-team">Listen to your team.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>That should go without saying - if all decisions are made by the C-suite with little to no regards to what your employees think, well, don&amp;rsquo;t be surprised if your current team will walk on you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You literally can&amp;rsquo;t have a good product if the team behind it doesn&amp;rsquo;t believe in either the product itself or your capabilities in shipping it to the market. Nobody wants to spend months of their lives on something that will be binned eventually and won&amp;rsquo;t ever see the light of day.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="give-options-to-grow">Give options to grow.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re a tech company that uses PHP and Java 6 and you&amp;rsquo;re wondering why the median tenancy is 6 months - well, read this sentence again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t think there&amp;rsquo;s another field that is as competitive as IT and grows as fast - not saying that you should flip your current stack on it&amp;rsquo;s head but maybe introduce something new? Maybe &lt;a href="mailto:hello@akondas.com">email somebody&lt;/a> and get them to introduce Go within your company? IDK&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="grow-as-a-company">Grow as a company.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Simple things as, I don&amp;rsquo;t know, having a nice maternity package or having inclusive socials - not everybody wants to socialise face-to-face, maybe the online social you did a year ago in the middle of C-word was a big hit - why won&amp;rsquo;t you do it again?
Or just have nice, 6-months pay reviews - you&amp;rsquo;re moaning about &amp;ldquo;how hard it is to retain people&amp;rdquo; but you have yearly salary reviews and you do 5% pay increase then - have you seen how high inflation went this year?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="real-life--linkedin-life">Real life =/= LinkedIn life.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I always like how companies are promoting themselves as &amp;ldquo;the best place to work&amp;rdquo; with having really big turnover (it&amp;rsquo;s not really hard to figure this out in these days).
Glassdoor reviews maybe doesn&amp;rsquo;t reflect the reality 100%, as a lot of these reviews might be written after something has happened in the workplace so it&amp;rsquo;s filled with bad voodoo and really bad emotions - but they do have some truth in them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aim for your company to reflect your marketing team game in the real life. And revert to point no.1 - listen to your employees, they will &lt;strong>literally&lt;/strong> tell you what&amp;rsquo;s wrong with the company and, most probably, will propose how you can fix it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="be-a-man-of-your-word">Be a man of your word.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re giving somebody a raise mid-year and you won&amp;rsquo;t give them another by the end of the year (even if your company policy is to have a EOTY salary review), just tell them. Don&amp;rsquo;t play the card &lt;em>but we&amp;rsquo;ve already given you the raise, why do you want another?&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Who&amp;rsquo;s the joke here then, the raise or you?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="as-a-recruiter">As a Recruiter&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="dont-waste-time">Don&amp;rsquo;t waste time.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As a techie, honestly, I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to respond to yet another cold email that asks for my number and if I&amp;rsquo;m interested to talk about one-sentence intro to a workplace. It&amp;rsquo;s not Tinder, you won&amp;rsquo;t buy me with &lt;em>great opportunities&lt;/em> or &lt;em>generous equity&lt;/em>. Just give me the job description, salary and what you need from me and I&amp;rsquo;ll 10 out of 10 times respond.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="if-youre-here-for-the-numbers-youve-chosen-the-wrong-profession-pal">If you&amp;rsquo;re here for the numbers, you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen the wrong profession pal.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Again, this goes together with no.1 - if you&amp;rsquo;re using LinkedIn to send cold invites and then you&amp;rsquo;re moaning that nobody responds to them and your cold-emails allowance is gone - well, do you really need to work in recruitment?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The best recruiters I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with, even if I didn&amp;rsquo;t take the job, were treating me as equal - we&amp;rsquo;re both in this game for money, for me in long-term, for you in short-term bonus. Help me and I&amp;rsquo;ll help you.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="know-the-limits">Know the limits.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Oh, this is the best one. I knew a recruiter who was so eager to get me across that was messaging me privately on WhatsApp or researching my profile on Facebook.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, kudos for proper research but it&amp;rsquo;s a work relationship. It&amp;rsquo;s creepy as hell when you are writing to me in the afternoon to ask &lt;em>what&amp;rsquo;s up?&lt;/em> or calling me and telling me &lt;em>so, I&amp;rsquo;ve found out that your best friend is moving to Canada, have you knew about it?&lt;/em> (both are true btw). Know where the boundaries are, if we&amp;rsquo;ll end up becoming friends, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not overnight.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="as-a-human">As a Human&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This one is easy in my opinion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just be fair and honest with yourself. We&amp;rsquo;ve all been in situations where you had to take the job because otherwise you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to pay the bills but, currently, we are the ones who can negotiate upwards. You should always, ALWAYS negotiate - it&amp;rsquo;ll show you how open the company is and how much dialog you can have.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="just-dont-be-a-dick">Just don&amp;rsquo;t be a dick&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>That has become my mantra for the last few years - if you are true to who you are, you&amp;rsquo;re not doing any bad things and not making other lives miserable - then you should be fine.
Work out where you want to be, how to get there and enjoy the ride. Remember that all plans, however great, might change - embrace the change and grow.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="but-i-really-want-to-be-one">&amp;hellip;But I really want to be one!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Well, I can&amp;rsquo;t help you there. I&amp;rsquo;d maybe say &lt;em>choose your battles wisely&lt;/em>? I really don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But however shitty you&amp;rsquo;re aspiring to be, don&amp;rsquo;t be a complete and utter dick and let go a ton of your people &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X7GVklRqHRY">over a video call&amp;hellip;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>